[Music]
after the wife's hand out what you win
for next Tuesday and there is a ball
socket hand outage that I get from how
[Music]
are you good I'm glad you're making all
the classes oh good very welcome okay
[Music]
all right this is where the course
really begins you should have a sense of
what the fundamentals involved in value
investing our water understands that we
want an appropriate search strategy
where you're going to look that's going
to put you on the right side of the
Train where you're going to be better
informed than the people on the other
side of your trade or at least making a
more extensible decision that's the
first thing second thing is you want an
approach to valuation and Industry
understanding that is what a degree of
judgment goes about how to process the
accounting information and how to figure
out the context in which the nature of
the industry and that economic model the
industry puts that accounting
information that leads to superior
valuations to the run-of-the-mill
performance of your competitors because
this industry is by its nature a
zero-sum industry beyond that want to be
good and systematic at looking at the
collateral information are the insiders
buying or selling have you made this
mistake before is this an area where
somebody with your particular makeup
should be competing and finally you want
to have an idea of either the demand at
risk the people you're going to hear
from for the next 16 sessions are all
the evidence of their performance
indicates outstanding at doing all those
things are you're implicitly or
explicitly I take no credit for that
despite the fact that some of them are
actually a product of earlier versions
of this
it is their ability to take that basic
model and build it into a way they don't
know nobody I think over the last how
many years have you been wearing the fun
eight nine years have over the last
eight to nine years has done that
significantly more successfully than our
speaker tonight who is Lilu graduated
from the business school went
immediately into the business of
bringing the hedge fund get it first for
julian robertson with extraordinary
success and a six moved on did you think
that for himself and his old professors
with even I have to admit more
extraordinary but beyond that I think
what you want to pay attention to is how
basically get support all the
developments together in his own
inimitable style and with that by the
way let me actually say one more thing
the speakers are going to hear from have
very different attitudes towards risk
and very different degrees of optimism
which our particular night out and
particularly the way in which they do
invest we lose background is having
survived as a leader of the gentleman
square protests and escape with his wife
in some sense eight he's very optimistic
and he after living with that kind of
risk I would keep that in mind as you
listen how he goes about dealing with
this environment in being a professional
investor and having to outperform all
the rest of the world
[Applause]
Hey well what Bruce said about me must
be true because my evidence is my wife
actually showed up to listen to me
tonight now I can guarantee that is not
happy in our home
[Music]
and also I really felt terrific coming
back to this class I mean this class in
many ways is really what to meet my
career about 15 years ago at the time
actually I wasn't even as students at
business school I was accidentally
brought into a lecture I think of
basically part of this class and the
speaker has a funny name that really
reminds me of some kind of bull fail
entries anyway in the middle of this
speech listening to Warren that light
bowl kind of just went off and I figured
that I can do something in this business
and of course at the time I was a pretty
desperate you know recently escaped from
China I didn't know it anybody have a
very little you know connection
whatsoever and didn't have any money in
fact I was deep in debt and it was a
horrible he worried about how do I ever
make a living in this country and I
really didn't go up with a capitalist
culture either so and so in the middle
of his speech I thought well what he
said about investing really just so
different from my perception of a stock
market and and the more I think I've
thought about it I'm more I thought oh
well gee this may be something that I
can do now I suppose that most of you
who chose this class I understand is
very difficult to get into this class at
least it was when I was a student
it's maybe kind of a self-selected group
of people who are already somehow by is
due to all the value investing how many
of you really consider yourself a value
investor or more predisposed into
manually investing how many of you sort
of know for sure you're going to be kind
of asset management business so roughly
the same number of people who really
want to be an asset management business
have sort of a already consider yourself
as a value investor so who can really
tell me what are the one or two things
that really sort of defines a value
investor from everybody else anybody
yes chase usually right there
so another way to think that you sort of
feel yourself is more of a owner of a
business in the sentence and therefore
your fortune rise up and down with the
nature of the business a how
things to add please yeah you're sort of
you demand a margin of a safety in the
sense anybody else right right right
well that's pretty summarizer that
they're basically three attitude streak
out of the teachings of a Ben Grimm that
a you think yourself has basically not a
paper shuffle or in the sense you you
really think yourself as as owner of the
business and be you sort of you know you
you would demand a huge margin of safety
when approaching investment and see that
somehow you sort of think everybody else
is different so this this is where the
mr. market analogy come in this is three
things actually kind of a they all you
know come in to really coming from one
perception which is you know is you you
think yourself is an order of business
rather than kind of a kind of owner of a
piece of a paper and and and and you own
a small piece and therefore you really
don't control the business and therefore
a sort of is almost self-defense to
demand a large margin of safety because
whatever value you perceive them you
know to be there because he can't
control it and then because you thought
you're really owning the business and
therefore you really don't care you know
if you're older business you don't treat
that all the time
and so therefore you think that you are
somewhat different from just about
everybody else in the market participant
but then the question is we really feel
your owner of business why do you want
to be the stock market the stock market
is not created for this type of a people
is that right the stock market is a
created is a freshly so that everybody
can go in and go out is that right
anybody have a view on that one who can
tell me that
acity you think is really kind of
managed by value investors anybody have
any guests with that kind of a
perception we just talked about there's
no real study but there are a number of
attempts of a study including one
actually by a professor next door in the
law school a low a low esteem yeah and
which really kind of put it a roughly
under 5% of all asset that actually is
consistent from what we just talked
about it now you are really nod to the
majority you are actually a very very
minority and the stock market is really
not created for you it's created a for
the ninety five percent of all the other
people and that's really where your
opportunity is and that's where your
challenge is so to understand that
before I go into a management in your
business is it really short nerely
important and that's really when I
that's what I first learned when like
when I came here and listen to above it
that's one thing that's stick in my mind
and that really sort of helped me to
position where I am because I really
know by then what kind of a person I am
I think most of your challenge
especially those of you who really want
end up in the managed management
business and I'm actually tonight
primarily address to that group of
people sorry for those people that are
not you were your biggest challenge is
really to understand whether you are
that 5% of the PERT people or you were
the 95% of the majority and you might
think that because of the training
because you do this you sort of you know
intellectually or theoretically bias or
to also that small minority group of
people you'll be amazed you know how
much it would have change you know my
career is sort of a take a little yeah
twist as well I always kind of arrived
my own fun you know part of the time
when Bruce automation was Julian was
really a sort of when he invited me to
really share all of it with him because
he sort of invited a whole bunch of a
fund managers that he invested him and
also share a story
ideas and that's when I sort of get a
much better understanding of how the
ninety-five percent of other people
really operated and you know it is
tempting because you know why 95 percent
of the people don't do you know what you
guys are here try to do
despite the spectacular success of
Warren Buffett Charlie Munger why is
that anybody have a reason why is that
why there's only yes yeah what
emotionally is a very difficult but if
you think of that you know it's very
convincing that value investor is over a
long period of time really have much
much better kind of returns
you know you think that's where the
money is you know even if is emotionally
difficult you think they wouldn't change
it any other reason right right right
right we actually are very close to the
point I think that the real answer is
that's really where the money is
why that's where the money is because
the market is really created for those
group those kind of a people we're
really thinking of trading in and out
all the time and therefore that they
will pay attention to the short term and
therefore that if you put up with that
requirement that's really where the
asset is going to find you and so as a
result that's a statistic de SPECT
it's a huge different disc rumba see of
a performance of that 5% have a
spectacular return consistently over a
long period of time 95% of the money or
something close to that probably would
always reside to somewhere else and it's
if that's where the money is you know
most people would naturally would end up
there
so my first kind of a point I want to
leave with you is really to understand
who you are because you won't be tested
through all this period of time do your
future career development that you're
going to really have to really face this
to
to ask yourself whether you're value
investor you're not mad even faster now
if for whatever reason that your
personality is a build to be a value
investor that probably means that you
somehow you know genetically mutated
through out of the the process of
evolution that a are very comfortable
being in a minority which is not really
very natural to human beings you know
throughout our human evolution process
the most of us survive it because we
stick with the group in phase of large
memos that's the only way we can we can
survive and so it is really over you
know tens of a thousands of years of
evolution it really need a deeply
ingrained into the your genes but
occasionally you will find a small
percentage of people really survive
despite the fact that they really have a
different kind of a gene is almost
through a mutation process that that
group of people survived so there's the
first thing you have to really be very
very comfortable you know being very
much by yourself and therefore you would
naturally adopt an attitude you're right
not because other people agree with you
but because your reason your evidence or
right it is common sense
but of course as people said common
sense is at least a common commodity
most people don't think that way and
secondly that you would have probably
spend most of your time truly be an
academic researcher instead of so-called
a professional investor most of the time
you're going to spend as a professional
investor as a value investor not a
professional investor is really to be an
academic to be a researcher to be a
journalist actually to basically be have
insatiable curiosity to really and try
to figure out how just about everything
works because investing really the more
you know and the better of you are as an
investor and so you you just have to be
naturally interested
and occurs just about everything any
kind of a business politics science
technology and humanity history poetry
literature everything really affected to
your business basically so you almost
have to wait it you you know I don't
want to scare you don't have to it will
help you it will help you and then
occasionally you want to find a few
insight that all of those studies that
really gave you tremendous opportunities
than other people just for whatever
reason couldn't deal with either
psychologically somebody said or were
because of the limitation for the
thinking or because of the institutional
imperative of the institution that
belonged to all sorts of a different
reasons and then you go through
find out is the business that
opportunity you're given is that cheap
is the business a good business is the
management to somebody that I can trust
either because they're good or because
the external checks are sufficient and
what else is missing and that why this
opportunity presented to me so you go
through all this checklist and you feel
comfortable and then you'll just have to
really go over that last a psychological
barrier to basically do it so let's just
go through a couple of examples
unfortunately what I'm doing today
you know I no longer talk about what we
own so I pick up a couple of examples of
what I owned in the past you know I
started this business in late 97 and you
know along the way being through a
couple really traumatic events you know
one is sort of the Asian financial
crisis and then the technology bubble a
couple of the different things but you
know those period of a time you tend to
have more interesting opportunities
let's start with the let's go back to 98
so it was a fall in 98 and I tell you
the search that I go through are very
simple because I'm interesting all sorts
a different business I usually just get
in menus you know I got hooked a tube
annuli while I was a student here you
know every issue as it comes out I just
you know love to read the whole thing
from beginning to end because that's
really the best kind of education if you
want to have an encyclopedia knowledge
base and database
which you have to so just go through
that to page after page after page is
just enormous ly helpful and the first
thing I always check is sort of the new
low list you know that the new kind of a
low is the bloke low is a PLO is
available that we attract me more than
the new high list now this actually I
don't have any more of my copies I get
rid of that so I asked them for reprint
and the number is not right I mean I was
looking more of somewhere around I think
is a September or something
August that when the stock was roughly
around 28 so this is a 46 it's not right
so this roughly call that 28 to 30 now
you look at this one you know what is
the first thing jumps to you somebody
give me a quick read yes right yeah yeah
anything else yes right right
anything else now if you're in investors
you don't really care where it was
traded to before actually oh hi Carol I
tell you what I look for is that first
look at evaluation and if the valuation
doesn't fit I don't even want to really
kind of a go beyond it so what do we
know about the valuation yes yep yeah
that's a good point and what is the
Constitution of the book value so
everything you know every time you'll
see is a below Book value you want to
say what what's in the book what's in
the book how much is the book what
now that's simple you can just you know
call it a 28 and then you've got a what
eleven and a half million shares roughly
three hundred something low three
hundred million just to approximate you
don't have to really do all the quick
was and he'll see where it is now the
the working capital is almost a three
hundred million in a sense and of course
it was the end of the q3 and in retail
what would you know about kind of an end
of a q3 in retail is that this is really
where you know you're you're kind of a
quick encyclopedia knowledge it really
helps you all retails have built up a
huge amount of immigrants
the last quarter so you look at back to
the previous years to say what is it
normal like because is it going to
really collect a lot of a cash at the
end of the year so you say okay so
there's a 300 million it's almost the
entire book value roughly 275 million is
in the is in the working capital
everything else cancel each other and so
you'll probably collect about a hundred
million cash at the end of the quarter
if you look at the other two years so
roughly you got a 200 million liquid ass
and applause 100 million no fixed asset
and if you do you know a little bit more
study you're gonna see there's entirety
buildings real estate basically so 300
and you're treating roughly 300 million
and so 200 million is is a liquid asset
and then about 100 million is is in real
estate so you've got a pretty decent
protection on the downside so what do we
know about the earnings the cash flows
and the ones you want to really pay most
attention is basically kind of the the
pre-tax and pre interest earning the
unleveraged and you want to compare that
it was unleveraged capital that is
needed in the business against your
sense of what kind of business you're
having how much of their making give me
a quick sense how much is that well if
you're skilled it shouldn't really take
you more than one second to find that
out you got 13 percent roughly of
operating margins of 800 what 800 850
million so you get roughly 100 million
hundred ten million and what is your
deployed capital how much capital is
deployed in the business roughly
you
you wouldn't have roughly about say 200
million in the in liquid asset and then
about a hundred million in buildings and
then the 200 million of liquid has a
probably a hundred millions cash so
you'd roughly have a 200 million
deployed a capital and roughly returns
about a hundred ten million dollars so
your return on your deployed of capital
roughly around fifty percent at that
point so that's not a bad business so
you shouldn't read it I mean you start
with say you give a five second look at
me you say hey the business I don't care
you know all the other things the
business was trading roughly you know
read around the book value book that it
was pretty claim is basically consists
of a tangible
the quit asset working capital plus you
know a hundred billion real estate and
and the deploy to capital is basically
2/3 of that and and for that 200 million
you'll return roughly 100 million or so
and so they shouldn't be bad business to
begin with so next thing you check sort
of a why this whole thing sort of fall
apart at that point
sort of a missing I mean whenever you
see something like that you say wow
that's not a bet you know if I owned the
whole business remember you're always
sort of a think as yourself as business
owner if I owned this business if I
can't buy the whole business at this
price you know you probably want to own
it and it's actually is not a bad name
right most people recognize Timberland
as a brand right so what is the reason
at a time was torn out is that that was
the height of the Asian financial crisis
that all their competitor is especially
Nike and Reebok
see their sales especially in Asia
falling out of a cliff and so the whole
contingency sort of all their perils
that all the retailer's of shoes and
international brand anything that has
exposure to Asia all fall apart but what
else is going on so you try you try to
check you know what other people are
thinking about this mm-hmm you know you
you you you may not really listen to the
advice but you want to really know what
other people are looking at so you check
to see whether there's any analyst
report it turn out there's no enemy's
report nobody covered this well for a
company is doing about a billion dollar
in sales is always a reasonable company
is a big brand so why nobody kind of a
cover about this any possible reasons
you can speculate yes
which is a good or bad for you fabulous
for you fabulous for you and you go back
to see 10-15 years the good thing about
Value Line is you go back to 10-15 years
and you see whether they ever really
need to that money what did you find in
the business over the last whatever
years it's been growing the
profitability has improved dramatically
over the recent years but has always
been pretty profitable and therefore
they're neither full financial market is
very limited any other reasons
what's the ownership structure yes yes
what do you mean my family owned they
own 40% of it how much voldie control
they have a hundred percent vote
basically ninety-eight percent right so
immediately that turn off a whole bunch
of people and then you see what you know
how the investor has been basically
reacting to them in the past you can do
a quick kind of a data search and this
is what really why you know I say that a
a investor should really
investigative a journalist because we
have a journalist here I'm sure if I ask
the journalist look at this question you
know there the first thing you were to
say would it go through all of this
question I just asked
and pretty easily you confine all the
answers and very quickly and so you've
got to have a very active Eric hearers
mind and you just can't would it really
satisfy was Eddie bogus answers
otherwise you can't really be in this
business so you go and you'll find
there's actually a whole bunch of a
different shareholder lawsuit now you
have owner owns a forty percent owns an
almost a hundred percent of the vote and
those of a shareholder doesn't have a
vote and you have no analysts cover them
and there are a whole bunch of
shareholder lawsuit so immediately that
if you don't know anything about the
business if he or the 95 percent of the
other investor what conclusion you would
have jaw what will be your conclusion if
you were kind of you know a normal
mutual fund or a hedge fund trading
oriented
investment manager what would you say to
this situation now that you'll find all
this information please yep right
anything else yes right right anything
else yes
yes anything else you guys are not
skeptical enough what would you really
worried about ooh that that management
might be milking money from the company
might be manipulating their books
because they control everything there is
virtually no there virtually no
constraints on what they do and the fact
they're a whole bunch of a lawsuit it
tells you they're complaining about
something right so what do you do next
what do you do next well yes that's one
thing anyway out what absolutely you
download every single piece of the
document of the court cases every single
case and read them from page
and that's why I was saying that if you
don't have a curious mind if you just if
you just want to do it because you want
to make money out of the chances are
you're not going to do this you have to
really figure that I just you know I'm
just so curious is what's happening this
this doesn't add up and you have to dig
every single thing as you read
everything as I did the first apart it
takes a less than you know a couple
minutes you look at that one you say
that's really wanted
there'll be all the questions you read
it leaves you to all of that so upon
possibly find all the cases I can find
you know all the cases really it would
be one thing actually there's basically
one complaint is just multiple filings
that you know somebody really say well
they used to provide to some guidance
and they didn't deliver and the investor
get pissed off and so the order also get
piss off you can you know vividly see
his defense you can get a sense of his
personality by reading those document he
said you know what I'm not gonna do this
anymore
I'm not gonna talk to the street I'm not
gonna give any guidance I don't need a
damn dollar from anybody else the
business is wonderful okay so that
remove a big cloud so the next thing
what do you do well if they really run
this run this way the next question is
okay maybe there are not crooks but are
they good managers how do we know that
other decent people how do we know about
that
how do we go about to find that what do
you do
sure anything else you can do
how do you know either personality yes
good idea
great what do you call what do you tell
the neighbors what do you just say go to
hell
you'll hung up but most people will tell
you what go to hell but it's nice try
anything else yeah that's right there
was no Google back then but that's a
good idea
now you want to the point is you got to
really go
no I says again again you know just
happen to have a journalist here but I
always view this job as investigative a
journalist
most people who have build businesses
also have a big personality
have a history you can go to audit never
leave the trail of evidence of what kind
of person they are and what they have
done how they deal with the different
situations it is not that difficult but
you have
most professional managers wouldn't
really consider that as a part of the
business but I'm telling you you're the
5% if you end up to be the 5% maybe
you're not but if you try to be that 5%
that's what you do you go to see their
community you go to the Church of
synagogues and you goes you know you go
visit everybody you sort of get yourself
to be part of that and you introduce
yourself to all their friends and
families and neighbors don't just call
them go there spend a few weeks there
it's worth it it's worth it just to
spend as much time you can possibly be
to try to find him find what he had done
to his a community what does neighbors
and friends tell about me to say about
him that tells you more about this
personality and you want to find the
family dynamics this fellow actually
only graduated high school never really
wouldn't have a college relatively
simple guy but a nice decent guy has
been very philanthropic go to synagogues
but not terribly devoted
but a more interesting thing has a son
who actually went to business school as
well it was actually my age at the time
was in the mid 30s early to mid 30s and
as the time already assumed to be a CEO
of the company so I did all the things
that suggest to all of you I did it
further and I find that what this Suns
all the board of the Father and the sons
on and I find a one of the board the
site of a song actually is a run by a
friend of mine so I invite myself to be
on the board
so I join on the board along with the
son and would become very close friend
and then I really know in that family is
turnout this is one of the most Anna
marring family I've ever met there are
people of the highest integrity they're
wonderful and they also happen to be
brilliant businessman so after all of
that and the stock actually still
trading right around 30s and so that's
sort of you kind of answered you sort of
an oh you know did I miss anything you
sort of a same probably not I didn't
miss anything
the other 95% just don't know or their
industry imperative does not allow them
to do anything about it so what do you
do at that point what do you do by how
much you want to buy let's suppose we
have $100 what
why how much is that 200 okay well I
like to talk to this class because you
guys are not polluted it yet now if you
go to join the fund the first thing
people were to tell you is oh gee don't
do anything more than 25 basis points
and then your goal is maybe 50 basis
point and you do one percent as 100
basis when they use a basis point so
every number sounds big you know boy
we're gonna do 50 basis point there's a
big deal that's what is it like that's
what is it like so keep your innocence
because right now what you're thinking
is the common sense think about how much
effort you put in together stem thing
right think about how good it is you
have virtually no downside you're
treating roughly about five times and
the next thing I did is I actually have
been to all the different store to see
why in the last few years the margin
improved substantially it's turned now
there was a fad going on in the in the
especially in the inner cities that all
the little kids want to have you know
the Timberland shoes and jeans and poor
the things that you know all the store
manager tell you they couldn't really
get enough stock and you look at how
much of their international business
which is actually in shoes in in Asia
less than 10 what they make out of that
less than 10 10 percent out of the 10
percent of the 27 percent so you
calculate all day you say that all of
them are gone you're losing money so
what it reduce your earnings by less
than five percent so I put a shitload
anybody know what happens afterwards in
the next two years I mean you guys all
have the internet you can check right
away really you should do that yes sure
that why do you want to listen to all
the you just do whatever you want
to do as I said you know you're right
not because other people tell you to
agree with you we're right because you
need to do that you need to check on
that all of those things should come to
you in no less than five minutes
otherwise you're just not a good analyst
if you're not going to handle you never
be a good investor seriously so you have
to at least technically train yourself
to be very very proficient with all of
that well the next two years this damn
thing went up seven times and the truth
of the matter is doing all those time it
was a propellant of our earnings and so
you do all this time you still did not
have any risk it's not like you're
hiding you know writing some technology
company after they doubled tripled you
expose yourself to a huge amount of
attacks it was an ever more than 15
times earnings never but if you treat
them from five times to you know to 15
times and the earning who's been growing
in that period of time 30% a year I mean
they're that up that add up and the
other
Gover as a CEO and he had the entirely
different ideas about how to run a
company
it was very articulate it's one of the
most articulate person ever met
Stu is so he doesn't mind to talk to
general analyst he initiates not earning
guidance but analyst meetings and the
first immediate guys who you know how
many people showed up it was him me and
another analyst three people three
people and the last analyst when I sort
of a woods kind of you know somewhere in
mm you know mm the room is just
absolutely filled with nearly 50 60
people
a major street burger house kind of
initiate some kind of a cover issue so
that's no I know when I have to sell so
everything anyway let's go back and say
hey you know time kind of flipping this
is sort of a year and a half ago yeah
because that's really when the lawsuit
occurred they did have a period of a
time well they do have a misstep at that
point because their product wasn't right
they bake they build their business
really on the reputation of this kind of
water proof that they're the first guy I
would really come up with his counsel
water proof and so they did you know
sort of mix the Sun and mix it signals
of both water proved to shoes and non
waterproof tissues and any marketing
that was a mistake
that was a mistake and he confused the
market and it confused the integrity of
their claim and they suffered but even
with that year the revenue pretty much
has still gone up I mean they have a one
year of a blemish most of the time they
have executed their business quite
brilliantly yes it does
that's why do you really buy anything
afterwards you don't have to you already
bought everything of 28 you know did you
know when they go up you don't you just
have to sit your ass on it don't have to
do a damn thing
that's good thing about really buying a
good business the business take care of
yourself I mean has a chase set your
writing up and down with the bow is with
the strength of the business and it yes
actually normally than a couple weeks I
mean all of those surprisingly it
doesn't take all that long but but when
the things happens you just have to
really give up day and night into it day
and night into it that's why I'm glad my
wife is actually here so let me know all
this missing pie what I was doing you
know the opportunity like that don't
come very often so Winnie when it comes
you have to seize it you have to do
everything complete but you have to do
it fast and that's why you have to train
yourself all those time and you don't
have to do a damn thing plug things into
a bank that's okay you don't have to buy
anything but when opportunity comes you
have to jump on it and that's what I did
when you finish all of the things it
doesn't take all that long but you take
intensive work for a short period of
time
yes well I'd like to read that one
mostly because is in itself is a good
activity I don't have to find anything I
learned then I'm curious about all
businesses and that's why when the
opportunity to come within a few second
you can tell you can smell it how can
you really develop their smell the only
way to do that is just reading page
after page and value line is
particularly good because it really puts
you know all sorts of a different datas
and all sorts of years you're not just
one year and so that's the you know
easiest way for you to really learn a
whole bunch of different businesses yes
I would really keep that confidential
but I shitload of okay let's go back to
a year and a half ago okay so this is a
fall and you know this thing come from
this book I mean this you know you know
this is you know this is like a stop you
know standard pour well you know every
every you know every broker has a book
in every country give you you know one
page summary of every company you know
it's just you know SMP has a book for US
companies and which I use but I prefer
to use value line as I said because of a
US company just give you more
information and for other countries they
don't have value lies you go with this
okay so I just flipping on that one at
that point you know there's a one page
you know jumps on so that's the page so
what people can tell you about that page
yes right what do you mean by cheap well
if you really think about you your owner
don't think about per shares okay so if
you just treat yourself from now on
they'll think about per share numbers
think yourself as an owner so give me
what is the market cap
come on it's simple come on and I
thought you guys all did a homework did
you anybody did homework not a one hand
raise your hand if you did it homework
one hand how the hell you're gonna make
in this business one head you did a job
good tell me what is your what is a
market cap okay no anybody else it's
very simple what is the ratio between
cream 1 $1 what yes just divide by a
thousand
so do that right now what is the market
cap what 87 million roughly about $12
roughly about what five and a half
million shares how much is that don't
use that one don't use it you know use
your could've do you know get used to if
you want to read a lot of company you
know there's a lot of a company this one
okay each page it should take no more
than five minutes and the only way to do
that is don't use those calculator just
get yourself into more of a mental
little things you can really look at
those things it immediately within five
minutes you get a pretty good summary of
the basic financial data so don't use
all of that tell me the numbers twelve
five and a half million
okay so sixty-seven million dollars if I
take five ten million doesn't kill you
what is their earnings last year
give me the kind of pre-tax number
come on you guys you're the Columbia
Business School
class you're the elite you expect to
make $150,000 as a base what do we
people pay you for what well how much is
that
give me the protector knew how much is
that pre-tax earning just to read a few
lines before it's College what is a net
income
12 as the six months double that and the
year before is what 24 mln pre-tax 31
million you're treating had a sixty
million dollars of market cap roughly
about two times
what's your working capital what's your
book value what is a book value come on
come on you guys have work to do this is
not good
Bruce I don't know what you're teaching
them come on
divide by a thousand is 236 million it's
simple 230 million dollars in book sixty
million market cap 25 million that
earnings of 31 million pre-tax earnings
how much is what is the constitution of
the book value
how do you really go about to do this we
have to probably go to the basics okay
who can tell me how do you really do
those things quickly just as an analyst
what do you say about it when people ask
me with you
how do you really within five minutes
tell me the basic sort of structure
financial in this company how do you go
about chase n
how about yours are roughly perfect
simple what are you using businesses use
some fixed asset as I'm working capital
that's it and the goodwill Z can really
not account on that but that's it that's
what you need to operate a business
that's what you mean by owner if your
owner you look at something like that
you should be able to tell right away
and if you can't do this well that's
bruises / fault I shouldn't really
afford to go I mean that's a pain take
you who you would learn right oh okay so
now here is the basic thing you've come
out of this one okay so this one is not
a gave you a whole bunch of a different
information right it tells you roughly
is traded a sixty million dollars in
market cap it has it roughly about
thirty million dollars in pre-tax
earnings and it has about 70 million
roughly 180 million dollars in fixed
asset come up with 100 to 140 or so
million in Book value so what does it
tell you what do you do next
you look at that one took you five
minutes you got this what do you do next
well how do we know it's cheap we think
it might be cheap but you're not
conclude it's not conclusive yet you
have to you have to go you know next to
find out and what exactly what is their
earning what is the book what is the
Constitution the working capital what is
you that in the fixed
right now I'm just basically using
common sense a common logic I mean this
is something you have to really think
you don't have to go through any you
know this is sort of a you're still kind
of a you know savable if you will if you
that's why all my employee ever had
really never went to business school and
never worked to free
kind of established many management firm
and some of them never had accounting
because I find it easier to tween them
that somebody who did clear it hasn't
really demonstrated here I mean if
you're sort of a goes through if they're
teaching the right way you should be
able to tell right there right away what
it is okay so we did some work and it
really takes enough know time of the 70
million in current asset you know how
much is it's all cash
Security's treatable securities of 180
million over the hundred eighty million
so-called a fixed income
well they recorded they owned a hundred
percent of a hotel they recorded a
thirty million is a book
they also own thirteen percent of a
department store we should record on the
book of thirty million it just so
happened that department store is next
page so is easy for me to find I turn a
pager on a violin depart the store I
discover it it is roughly had a market
cap of a six hundred million so thirteen
percent roughly gave me what what
roughly eighty million so the book can
really enter estimated the value by
another fifty million and they also all
three cable companies MIT 10 percent ish
and they also a whole bunch of real
estate and next I look at it that
department store they look at boy it has
exactly the same profile they're
treating roughly around the cash and
security they own about two three times
of their earnings and the Oh whole bunch
of a different asset turn out they're
the second largest cable operator as
well and the next thing I learned is
this department store really function is
more like a hotel it's not a department
store that we understand here they don't
take any inventory it basically provide
is more like a shopping mall and they
charge you to buy taking a percentage
off the top line of all the merchants
sell their stuff there okay so you edit
it all up here is what you have okay
you're paying sixty million dollars you
have a seventy million dollars in cash
this is no debt seventy million dollar
in cash you have another 100 million
your stock
as how much was that 170 million you
have a 30 million dollar is a hotel the
value hasn't been changed over the last
ten years and real estate in Korea has
it gone up dramatically over that same
period of time I went to career and look
at the hotel I look at all their
department stores and looks quite decent
to me
I check the recent transactions of all
the things in the neighborhood they all
indicate me and that value is more like
a two three four times of what is on the
book but supposedly I take it on the
book supposedly taken on the book let's
add another 150 million how much we have
right now roughly three hundred twenty
billion oh so which I paid a sixty
million and besides I'm earning of about
thirty million dollar a year what did I
miss
what did I miss
yes good question what about it
any evidence oh that could happen
right
terrific point absolutely a great point
anything else
great point anything else right anything
else what the liability because of
lawsuit you know what kind of a lawsuit
it could be lost to found a customer
that could happen to any company right
your reason that specifically for this
company or any company anything else
that's so far I haven't heard anything
about local market as if the only thing
I would really bother about those are
foreign investors what about the local
market
what about what other investors is
seeing and looking and thinking
good point look at it that's why I give
it to you I thought you're gonna do it
yes
what's that absolutely and how much is
it owned by the insiders well you don't
have a variance about 50% you've got a
whole bunch of different things against
you you also have a whole bunch of a
different thing than really in your
favor you have to go through all of it
each one and think rationally carefully
you have to add to that list of the
attitude of the local investors the
other people were buying because there's
nobody from foreign that really owned
this damn thing if you check that so you
go through all of that and we don't have
time to go through all of that
but you should and then you'll come up
with a solution I mean come up with your
decision as I have now I sort of own it
and what happens to the stock since well
again nobody's have any competitor
whenever you can check ok so I'll have
to charge that that a printout directly
from Bloomberg one is that the
department store it was treated around
to somewhere on 22
last I checked and went to about a
hundred and then and this one star was
12 last their check is there on 70 or
something each went up about five six
times
anyway well I give a couple of examples
just tell you that this type of approach
is not natural to an investor it's not
natural to you however if for whatever
reason you come to the conclusion that
you yourself your personality somehow
fit into this mutated gene pool that
this is something that you might really
and be looking to do the only thing that
I can add to that is that there's a lot
of money in it as has been completed
been repeatedly proved by people from
Ben Graham to buffin and everybody else
and I have been the probably just most a
grateful to this class to Bruce and
actually many years of before I came to
business school I took that class and
really changed me fundamentally but one
thing you do have to do is you got to do
it I mean that's why I was somewhat
disappointed if it would you know the
amount of work you put into places I
tell you I made hundreds of a thousands
of dollars just taking this class just
listening to the 14 15 people but it did
a lot of work I'm telling you you can
make a lot of money if you're really
into this not only just listen but do it
and we don't you guys you know how much
you spend you know coming to school here
how much you spent
what is the tuition as a board and all
of that stuff what is it now what
seventy altogether well you need at
least to make it that up I mean you
should at least of $70,000 back right II
you also have a two years you're not
making anything you gotta make that up
how do you make it up this is a terrific
way to do it and so that's sort of kind
of my last point I want to make is
the only reason I've come back and
really so I don't really talk about our
holdings anymore this is actually we
don't hold any of those two stocks
anymore the only way I do that is
because all that you know when I came
here
prior to business school and didn't do
in the business school you know most
people's do talk about names and I
benefit hugely hugely just by listen and
actually do it that's the difference and
it back then that was more than you know
10-15 years ago I made you know roughly
hundreds of thousands in one stock is
more than a hundred thousand back then I
think our cause was also a little bit
lower than the seventy I think I mean it
was I can't remember what was but but it
was a lower and but that's professor you
were into this class for this class is
different from any other classes because
there's no theory all
everybody's telling you is what works is
what works and if they don't tell you
that one well asked them they should
well yeah maybe they should but I did
okay
so this
sort of you you guys have a terrific
opportunity we'll be able to bid all the
poisons that got into Bruce's class and
if you don't really use this thing shame
on you
you've got to do it I mean those are
things really there is so much gold in
it that little pages the little books
those value lies all of them you've got
to use it you've got to do it I mean
you're young you have energy you know
what to lose there's nothing to lose yes
yes go ahead
well the most couple K so if your
analyst okay I always tell my Alice I
only need two things from you and if you
want to be analyst you need to be
analyst of course before you become a
good investor you want to provide
accurate and complete information
accurate and the complete most people
failed on both score big time and you
just have to go to that extra length you
order to get it done
if you can't succeed on that one you
can't succeed it succeed in this
business because most of the time you're
gonna stand alone basically against just
about everybody else and if you're not
really confident about what you know and
you're confident about your prediction
what other people know or don't know you
can't possibly be putting that kind of a
money when the things go into a free
fall when it looks like are you're
really losing all your money when
everybody else is laughing at you all
the smart guys so you must be able to
first to do accurate and complete and
the second thing in this business okay
most of money are not made on those
stocks I was just talking about your
biggest amount of money you're gonna
ever make is not from that those are
things really get your brain
and guess your basic business go and
give you the basic returns they do not
provide you outsized return even if both
stock went up five six times they do not
give you the outsized returns if you're
a value investor in the truest de sense
okay so there are two coos coos you mean
you can do with the Tweedy bronze you
can do the Ben Graham's or you can do
the buff and longer type which is more
of kind of what I'll interested in if
you want to be that one your return is
it going to come from a handful no more
than no more the number on the two hand
your entire life of maybe 50 years of
tremendous insight tremendous inside
you're gonna gain and no other people
have how do you really build that
insight there's no other way other than
basically continuous curiosity intense
curiosity continue as a study for your
whole life anything that works yeah
well I everytime I failed all those the
three scorers I made a mistake
time I didn't really get accurate
information I made a mistake completely
information being a mistake I do not I
thought I have it inside it was an easy
mistake every time I find all three
scores I've made a mistake and they're
plenty well on the big batch and I ever
made
yeah I don't recall we ever made a
mistake I show on the big bed now my
biggest a mistake actually is not making
a couple bed
because mistake I made is that during
the course of micro
that you know I had a spectacular
returners but I couldn't read any money
because every time I go out to talk to
people people basically said what the
hell you're talking about
I want a monthly I want a to weekly I
want a weekly returns I want you to go
up you know in a down market that's what
I wanted I want you to be a bank
accepted yield it better well and you
were hash fun aren't you anyway so but
that's you know I couldn't really what
in the end I sort of there was a couple
you know a couple years not
yes okay I'll do some of those
commissioner stuff I'm moving into
Julian Robinson's
learn from the best practice of other
hedge fund managers
somebody else kind of work on the
shorting all of that you know
essentially is sort of useless things it
turned out to be and are you sort of
busy in my cell with all sorts DaVinci
because if you're in shorting you just
have to treat there's no other choices
because you know you're upside 100
percent your downside is unlimited you
have to treat and so so you really and
your your your mentality changes and
what you can't no longer really you you
basically kind of put yourself into the
well what Charlie says about kind of if
you're doing things like that he was
just as if you you know bonder your
hands behind you in that ass-kicking
game like that it's true it really is
true and that was the period of time
that I probably have the biggest
opportunity of company that I have an
absolutely insight management that I
know that a treating below cash and it
subsequently went up fifty to hundred
times and I missed it I couldn't really
bring myself into it it doesn't really
fit into this monthly all this a
that was the biggest biggest mistake I
made is not how much money I lost it was
how much money I forgot I make I lose
money of course I do I do make mistakes
from time to time and usually you made a
mistake here when you haven't really
quite a finish all your work but you
like it you know enough so this is a
timber well you know at 28 awesome but I
haven't finished all the work and I said
on itself the probabilities with me and
but I added a lot long with the whole
process
well sometimes you know as you're sort
of finding more and more you prove your
face is wrong by then you lost twenty
thirty percent you sewed it okay so
you're wrong take the mistake run you
know move on but as is with you if you
buying stock at it with a sufficient
margin of safety the probability is with
you so if you do that long enough and
with you know relatively small amount of
bed of course you haven't know
everything then you're okay you're not
going likely to lose a lot of money but
if you can't really bet on the things
you know and you know you have inside no
other people have it and that's the
biggest mistake I cannot forgive myself
for making that mistake know if I still
might have a chance to do that yeah no
seriously you go through your life you
may not have no more than five ten
inside and you develop that one over
many many years with study some of the
things I'm doing really I find myself
doing that fifteen years ago
a study of the American company and now
fi the Asian counterpart and I find the
valuation that I like I find I can
really bet but I study that business for
fifteen years in between I know
everything about that industry and what
really make that business ticks you need
to have that kind of insight you order
to really
you can really swing with conviction and
if you cannot do that either
psychological or because you're
ill-prepared you just will never really
make any real mana money I mean you go
through either you do what Ben Graham
does with Tweetie Braun does it mean
you're gonna have your 10 15 percent a
year and you're likely to do much much
better than most of the professional
managers the 95 percent of other people
but you're not going to make the outside
return the Buffett have have been able
to achieve and you may not have that
opportunity throughout your life why
should be easy opportunity of that kind
that gives you a hundred thousand ten
thousand times their biggest ideas it
really give them ten thousand times
opportunity if done ones your life your
said why that could be why should I be
easy but definition they're not and you
require a whole bunch of a different
factors to come together you know what's
really Charlie would have called it what
is it term a lot of lot of pillows him
you've got all sorts of a different kind
of the things working on the conscious
level that subconscious level dislike
psychological political whatever you got
a whole bunch of a forces working
together you got a huge wave behind you
and you were the one who were the only
one who have the insight and is willing
to bet back to buy some complete
accurate information and a huge insight
and that's what you were sort of really
drives me in this business this exciting
is utterly exciting and you've got to
learn everything you know my interest is
just you know I started with the physics
mathematics and it got in true with
economic history law politics
I like everything I'll be interested in
everything and that's what you need it
you might need models or from biology my
wife has a PhD in biology and actually
I'd you know I learned a lot from her
over the years and actually some of them
helped my University except she didn't
know that's maybe why she's here to
check but anyway so you could have
learnt you have to learn from everything
you have to be intensely curious about
everything and occasionally you're gonna
stumble into one big opportunity new law
you still have plenty of things like you
know the timberlands the Hongdae you
know department store Asian is you're
gonna find those opportunities from time
to time give you a few times return
that's not bad yes not bad yes
depends you know there will be probably
there's ever she said meaningless
because the opportunities are different
you know there might be years you don't
really have a lot of opportunity and
then there might be years you have a lot
of opportunity it just sort of it all
depends on what really become available
to you but one thing I guarantee is they
don't really come in steady pace I don't
really have steady kind of once a month
once a week type of idea I never had
that throughout my career back into the
times you know when I started this thing
15 years ago when I was at Columbia at
the time I was undergraduate student
when I bought
um I think through all to that maybe
five six years of what I was in school
at college Law School in a business
school maybe I haven't maybe three four
big ideas then really pay off big and
you know how do you average that out and
then afterwards you know I get a little
bit better you know the things about
this progess you progressively get
better and better and better
to the point you look at page like that
it takes you in a couple minutes to tell
you right away whether something could
jumps out you can smell it when you see
something so you get better and better
and better so you might actually have
more opportunity or the market is just
not cooperating and you don't have a lot
of opportunity a good ideas
a year ago was by that's okay but I do
not want to a whole year goes by where
as I did not learn anything I do not
establish a good inside well at least I
thought it was a good inside or destroy
the inside I thought I had you want to
go through every day and learning
something it's a good mental discipline
to have and a year goes by you have to
learn a great deal well I wrote a book
and it gave a little bit of advancement
and somebody paid a small amount of
money and they bought the movie right
for that and but my negative in my war
net worth is a negative because you have
a whole bunch of borings but I have cash
and so that was pretty good
you know on balance you know my net
worth I mean is a cash is just couldn't
really offset it at that but I do have
cash so I was very very lucky in that
regard
well I wouldn't say there's only two
divisions all of the things you list
that's all searching ideas okay so when
I read a biologies and when I read
physics when I read history which is
really one of my favorite things it's
all searching ideas or I do business and
when I when I find an idea I want to
read it but if I find an idea that are
actionable say if I kind of one of those
things jumps out that's all I do
okay if I don't have I do the other one
and then the rest of the time is
basically with my kid and my wife we got
two little one little girl is one and a
half and three and a half and they're
really just you know I learn from them
too because to see how human cognition
really developed which is enormous ly
important when you try to really figure
out you see in my checklist is okay is
that cheap is that a good business who's
running it what did I miss you know I go
through all the checklists when I go to
the hooter what did I miss that is
hugely important understand psychology
to understand human cognition and no
other places is better than really
observing how humans develop those
cognition from early on and that's why
actually you know playing with my two
little girl is really helped me
tremendously as investor so I guess it's
all work
anything and in addition to all of that
I would also add one more thing okay so
you know I said there's a three things
distinguish value investor okay so
you've got business owner mentality you
have a different to time horizon
you demand a huge margin of safety but
he's all come from one thing which is
sort of a your business owner and you're
cautious business owner you can't
control the outcome of the management
therefore you demand a compensation it's
almost self defense of a margin of
safety and then because your business
owner you tend to be long term but they
all the same now people would ask me
okay if you're a business owner okay why
the hell you double with the stock
market stock market is now it's min is
not min for the business owners it means
for the people who can treat that was an
attraction of a stock market that's one
ninety five percent it would never buy
into this idea because if everybody's
supposed to everybody this would never
happened because of human nature but
supposedly a hundred percent of the
people all are you know value investors
would therapy a stock market no hell no
who would it by IPO we thought I appeal
where is the stock market come from
whether we're the secondary market come
from and Eve everybody demand a huge
margin why anybody would have sell to
you so that's why I started the lecture
by basically saying that you are
basically you you know you're not belong
to the stock market and there's but you
have to always always understand that
perspective and therefore to position
yourself properly and don't get carried
away but if you're really really truly a
business owner then you will be
attracted naturally sooner or later into
owning businesses and that's why Buffett
really left it monger left it each of
them runs a partnership for thirteen
years and they buy businesses run a real
company
or if you're really kind of you know
into that money if I do become sort of
private equity but that's more like a
real bit
in a sense but there was a evolution but
as long as humans
eval universe with that kind of
perspective to always find something to
do something profitable to do in the
market does not mean there's not
designed for them one is that the people
designed for a fundamentally flawed the
people that basically they're attracted
it because they want to treat and if you
want to treat you're bound to make a
mistake you're bound to really get your
emotions carried over there's a fear
greed or whatever the other emotion in
between you're bound to make mistake and
so when that happens there will always
always be room for guys like yous
you know supposedly you are that kind of
that 5% they will always be opportunity
for you okay
what's that that's a very interesting
question I evolved over that question I
used to have a philosophy if I don't
want to buy at that price myself that
was used to be my philosophy and I find
myself evolving a little bit from that
one because occasionally I find the
business a finite insight that I just
like the business so much I all of a
sudden find myself being a real owner
but basically saying somebody tried to
tempted to really get me to sell because
the price is very good you know the sort
of us it's not something I'm willing to
buy put it that way to that price but my
Hong tree this the probability is with
me that over the next ten years
and better and better and that's really
the law of a distribution of a good
businesses though leaders take a
disproportion amount of capital and in
certain industries that advantage the
huge advantage
and that's when I really began to think
okay so now you got to do a different
calculation okay you sell a you won't
may not be able to find another
opportunity to buy it back and be you
have to pay huge amount of tax because
at that point assuming you were right
you already accumulated a giant amount
of the tax which you have been borrowing
from government interest-free
essentially if you don't sell you're
basically borrow your leverage in your
position by a margin of a thirty percent
or something I mean in my case will be
fifty percent if you by the time you add
twelve percent and this you know stayed
all of the other stuff is like you know
you're forty fifty percent so you're
leveraging your position forty to fifty
percent interest free and it's not a
call upon and it's indefinite loan from
the government to you and so if you can
think and the business will be able to
deploy that capital and it returned that
roughly you know it's not even fifteen
percent is super business I usually find
is a fifty to 100 percent return on the
play the deployed capital and they were
able to deploy that boy that mathematics
get very very interesting very quickly
now the caveat for that one is you have
to be confident or reasonably confident
to be able to project that long and I
would say there's only a handful of
opportunities your entire lifetime
you'll be able to project that far off
if your investment banker all you do is
really project into infinity and that's
you know is a
everybody else know is a you
don't know you can't really project for
the next day
how do you know you can really go to you
know assumption of the next five years
and after another another five years and
infinity terminal Valley all the it
means nothing it means absolutely
nothing however I predict if you are
good if you're spending your entire
lifetime study you might be able to come
across over a course of a 50 years
career maybe five to ten opportunities
in which you can confidently project
with overwhelming odds next ten twenty
years at that point it'll sell
why do you want to self you've got a
government really lending your money 40
percent and compounded interest free and
it would have never really kind of asked
the money back and you can really
project in the business that deploy in
the capital in the order of 40 to 100
percent a year and also very tax
efficient and that's what you do that's
what you do because we don't have that
none of the businesses are really fit in
that category they're not that kind of
business I do have some business in my
portfolio they really kind of belong to
that category that I was just talking
about that's why I'm not talking about a
business of love that kind and you have
to really look for this you have to find
that at a vendor should they'd
established oh well whatever the reason
they established is getting stronger and
a stronger and stronger will be some
examples like that could be some an
example somebody studied us yes give me
example ok anybody else anybody else
give me some examples I mean that's
really where we're that's sort of you
know why the business school really kind
of a cause you of this much this is why
it may need you you you really get into
the frame of mind at least a habit of a
thinking about those things what really
make one business more successful than
the others what is their advantage why
they're making more and more and more
and more money as some is just doing
less and really go up and down why is it
have you discovered any business and by
the way the only way you can find that
is a by studying the ones we already
established yep is ethany Oh
what's that what really make for those
Moors at Marlborough more than the other
brands okay there's a good one
that's something but I really prefer but
and they also
that's a good one why's that
hey what's that
what yep
are you agreeing with all these so
they're basically reciting the portfolio
but yet other result has a grid I hope
you'll read to agree with that
the rosada have a great yes I do agree
with that but I want you to read a comma
something that Buffett haven't bought
something that you think of something
that it really is sort of he's already
in other words I don't want you just get
that one because you got a stand of
approval from somebody who's really
already firmly established as the
reading agency value investor
we gave me a name that he doesn't own
but also share those characteristic give
me a name
bursar portfolio okay that's a good one
why is that you're just oh you're
already kind of online
yeah what's that okay what tell me why
cellphone towers yep given all the
reason why the tower companies all
failing virtually all of them went
through bankruptcy no they came out
American tower closed there's a good one
one of my three company was American
topper but I was a student as a good one
any other one yes what Cory a rock
quarry in they
yep I find out why my yep mm-hmm good or
what any other one
hello bow to the ones everybody use go
ahead what's that why is that and what
about the competitors how many of them
are there you answer my question
anything else anything else what do you
use every day to do your research was
that a deal I okay what else you use
make sure you use computers and there's
millions of them say was a booty
materials what capital I feel
what good for and what Bloomberg was
introduced there was a bridge and
Reuters why they succeeded why Bloomberg
succeeded
sir you are interpret that they have to
looking for me so you can pretty much
track everything the only thing is that
they fail a little bit sometimes in
there we are
good answer anybody else could come up
with us well let's talk about Bloomberg
a little bit because this is something
you everybody use any other reasons you
can think of what okay okay
anything else what kind of research he
was a partner in Salomon Brothers the
bond trading department so they're their
analytics were far more detail okay okay
I switching cost-wise high switching
cost the people who use the machine of a
high opportunity cost of their time it
takes a long time to learn all the
functionality of Bloomberg for all the
offers I've heard this is the best
answer all of the things you talk about
is true but this is the really the most
important reason this is why that there
will be moment there will be in any
businesses well it reason this example
is because it's really you virtually all
business you are observe not all of them
really went through this dramatic
example but they all went through a
similar type of an examples of
transformation and sometimes something
has just happening in certain industry
that if you really went through
different industries you can almost tell
where that outcome is gonna come out
this is why you got a study this is a
fabulous case study of how you know a
company really come from nowhere going
into an industry that already half of
number of established long-established
players and somehow really began to make
it you know to little by little and a
certain point crossed a model stone
point after that that become a monopoly
where is the bridge where are the
reuters they're gone they're go
partially because partially because a
certain point exactly as you said at a
certain point anything that is a hard to
learn that is a highly highly
highly highly kind of a relied upon to
do your daily work what is your learn
that then thing you do not want to learn
that again and besides everybody else
using the same thing you have to be able
to communicate with your partners or
your colleagues anybody you collaborate
with
big business the winner takes all now
how do you really get to that point is
interesting question the suppose do you
have an opportunity to observe how this
industry evolved early on
supposedly you really observe an SC at a
certain point they have across that line
maybe it is the time when they're really
introduced them to every business school
so that you know when you graduate it
okay so you
well okay I have this one available
cheaply to me I'll learn this thing but
once I graduate going into the word I
don't want to learn that again and
everybody else are you who that whatever
is the time there will be a time that
that ayah has been crossed and
supposedly there is a public company
mostly you have a develop of that
insight that inside worth a shitload of
money
that's the kind of insight I was talking
about and that is a virtual monopoly
business and you find that again again
again all sorts of different business
this is not a little why Microsoft
succeeded real ensley over Apple when
Apple was one hundred percent of a
market share at the time when they came
in but little by little they crossed
that line so that when you'd be baited
between Apple or or Microsoft I say okay
I learned this thing because I have to
go to work and all the company that I
want to go they use
I don't have a choice do you even have a
choice today of not using Bloomberg what
is the cost of Bloomberg what is the
cost anybody know
nothing you can almost call that zero
they put some calls because they pay
themselves well what do they do do they
do research they don't do any research
what do they do they come to visit you
periodically almost every month and ask
you what do you use on daily basis
you're a traitor
you're 95% of the people uses you know
superstitious I mean if the certain
numbers works for you I look at that
number all the time active all of a
softwear for you only for you
how many functions Bloomberg has tens of
thousands does Bloomberg have a menu
hell no they don't want to give you a
menu they won't you get you individually
hooked on the two three or four or five
five six things and they can charge
who's that every day you're in the
business every treaty can redeem its
minions of again a law so you don't care
pay them a thirty thousand dollars a
year and you feel really charged with
ten percent every year more you don't
have a choice you don't have a choice
and they keep coming back to you because
they know you're a trader you're gonna
look for different things and so they
continuously to provide you the surface
and therefore you're hooked and a hooked
and a hook you're hopeless you're
absolutely hopeless beyond repair
meanwhile they would never give you a
menu but would never let you know the
cost is not a cost applies Waldo that's
why it's a fabulous business fabulous
business and then make each one of you
individually hook to one product which
cost them nothing and to the poor they
can really dictate and bully their
suppliers they pay them another all they
have is software's to get you hooked and
who gave them that information you don't
even do research they come to you what
do you need I give that to you think
about a switching from that think about
a competitor coming up with another
product that each individual you know
we're talking 100,000 profession
individually in a hundred thousand
different way how do you compete how do
you compete I don't know what do you
really why you set for I don't know
there's no menu now supposedly you know
that suppose it is a public company
supposedly you know the moment of the
inflection point do you want to invest I
would that's what I mean by either side
okay you'll study every business every
business I guarantee you
they all going through up and
I think in terms of the result as this
one but they all have more or less this
type of emit dynamics your job as a good
financial analyst as an investor as
value investor as a business owner is to
study that business all the time and
observe those trend and once you're
alive maybe
yours you'll be able to come up with
opportunity like that that is actually
available alike Bloomberg
now he's in that position of a selling
Alex he doesn't want to sell
why does that don't need his self
always I have a huge premium price they
will always be 30 times earnings but
he'll him lose a whole bunch of a lot
every time you want to sell it doesn't
need to sell that's when I really began
involved with my philosophy from if I
don't buy ourself into something that I
just said when you have things like that
you don't need to sell you don't need to
sell any other questions
oh sure any whatever questions yeah
after you making your investment right
honey mwah are you with the business and
management well it was all different you
know I've made a whole bunch of private
investment I serve other chairman of two
of them and on the board of several
including capital I kill you know I
don't when we build a capital idea we
intentionally copied the Bloomberg
business model and I'm really building
another model and then really copied the
same one for the engineers basically any
high professionals the needs of that
kind of things so you know you know all
the inside you learn can be applied for
different businesses in that case I'm
very active
none of the work a lot of the time and
the largest shareholder and a lot of
other was you know this how Native
artists are I couldn't even get a call I
couldn't even get a receptionist to
really take my call I went to their and
visit everything I so all the properties
but couldn't get anybody to talk to me a
by and large I like to know as much as I
can possibly know I want to be with
their friends
you know there's a Timberland situation
will become such a great friend the CEO
the son actually become a my investor so
that's the kind of relation I want to
have
turn Eddie but you always try it you're
always try
that everyday business decisions you can
learn you can observe you wouldn't know
the dynamic of that particular industry
at that particular moment and nothing is
constant that's the interesting about
business nothing is constant and that's
why I have to keep relearning things the
things you sort of you concluding all
the ones the analysis we just went
through with it with Bloomberg maybe a
couple years is different I don't know
what will cause the difference but it
could be and I have also there observed
you take an example of Microsoft the
dynamic is different it's no longer the
same now you got a free software it
posts a completely different scenario
every business
constant all sorts of different things
couldn't cause that change and that's
good thing that's a good thing that's
why people who is active mind and really
actively prepared and have the
psychological temperament to be able to
act when he really sees inside an
opportunity will always always have a
chance to be fabulously rich and that's
the note
[Applause]